<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks &amp; workshops on Deden Istiawan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks &amp; workshops on Deden Istiawan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The happiest notebooks on Earth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-canssi-happiest-nb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-canssi-happiest-nb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notebooks hold a special place in every data scientist&amp;rsquo;s heart. They may treasure every moment creating their own, or commenting on others&amp;rsquo; notebooks. Or they may sincerely and truly hate notebooks. But notebooks are useful. How could we &amp;ldquo;imagineer&amp;rdquo; better notebooks? I’ve made and read hundreds of notebooks in the past decade. In this talk, I share key principles for developing happier notebooks – ones that are more fun to write, more fun to read, and more fun as an onramp to the next ride.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The happiest notebooks on Earth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-observable-happiest-nb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-observable-happiest-nb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notebooks hold a special place in every data scientist&amp;rsquo;s heart. They may treasure every moment creating their own, or commenting on others&amp;rsquo; notebooks. Or they may sincerely and truly hate notebooks. But notebooks are useful. How could we &amp;ldquo;imagineer&amp;rdquo; better notebooks? I’ve made and read hundreds of notebooks in the past decade. In this talk, I share key principles for developing happier notebooks – ones that are more fun to write, more fun to read, and more fun as an onramp to the next ride.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The untold story of palmerpenguins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-user-penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-user-penguins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;palmerpenguins&lt;/strong&gt; R package provides a modern, approachable dataset containing body size measurements for three penguin species that nest on islands throughout the Palmer Archipelago, Western Antarctic Peninsula. Since &lt;strong&gt;palmerpenguins&lt;/strong&gt; was released on the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN) in July 2020, the package has been downloaded over 340,000 times, was quickly adapted for use in other languages including Python&amp;rsquo;s seaborn package and Google&amp;rsquo;s TensorFlow datasets, and has become a go-to option for data science and statistics educators worldwide. In this talk, we share the untold story of the &lt;strong&gt;palmerpenguins&lt;/strong&gt; package. From original data collection on rocky Antarctic shores to CRAN submission and beyond, we describe the penguins&amp;rsquo; journey from polar research project to global teaching product. What started out as a simple methods paper for a dissertation project turned into a widely used data science product mainly because of initial efforts to make the data publicly available and easily accessible by others. The success of the &lt;strong&gt;palmerpenguins&lt;/strong&gt; R package underscores the importance of proper data archiving for unknown future applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering women in data (science)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-rladies-cologne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-rladies-cologne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies Cologne is kicking off with a roundtable on &amp;ldquo;Empowering Women in Data (Science)&amp;rdquo; on February 21, 2022, at 7 pm CET. We are excited to have four fantastic speakers from across the globe working in different fields to share their experiences, tips, tricks, and challenges with us! 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our four amazing panelists are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨ Alison Hill (Ph.D., Senior Data Scientist, AI Strategy &amp;amp; Innovation @IBM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨ Ana Carolina Leote (PhD Candidate @ Cologne Graduate School of Ageing Research)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨ Angélica Becerra (Data Scientist @ cynkra GmbH)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨ Nina Hauser (Head of Data Literacy @ CorrelAid e.V.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy your mental models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-rug-mskcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2022-rug-mskcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I shared some lessons learned from teaching and learning tidymodels over the past two years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown Notebooks for Scientific Communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-agu-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-agu-panel/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;speakers&#34;&gt;Speakers
  &lt;a href=&#34;#speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alison Hill, RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fernando Pérez, University of California, Berkeley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simon Goring, University of Wisconsin / Leah Wasser, Earth Lab at CU Boulder / Laura DeCicco, USGS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loren Shure, MathWorks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugh Shanahan, University of London / RDA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Erdmann, American Geophysical Union&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kenton McHenry or Dan Katz (moderator), University of Illinois&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;panel-abstract&#34;&gt;Panel abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#panel-abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As science becomes more and more dependent on data and software, capturing these elements of the modern scientific procedure has become critical in achieving reproducibility. Computational notebooks have emerged as an increasingly valued way of capturing not only the traditional elements of a scientific paper but also the software steps in an executable and reproducible manner. As part of the 2020 EarthCube Annual Meeting, the EarthCube office, Leadership Council, and Technical Architecture Committee experimented by issuing a call focused on notebook submissions as peer reviewed publications. The call was well received by the community: 21 Jupyter notebooks were submitted, and 12 of these were accepted for publication. As part of the 2021 call for notebooks, the idea of expanding this call to more types of “notebooks” is being discussed, with the goal of eliciting submissions from a wider group of researchers, who may be more comfortable with other notebook technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed session will bring together representatives from the major “notebook” efforts, efforts such as Jupyter, RStudio, and commercial efforts such as MATLAB live scripts. Presenters will discuss the latest developments in each of their technologies, emphasizing elements that support the notions of ease of use, long-term executability, interoperability, and software publication. Lessons learned from building a geoscience-focused notebook directory, notebook template, and long-term preservation in AGU’s ESSOaR will be discussed as well as how this relates to international efforts to elevate notebooks and make them FAIR.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk-abstract&#34;&gt;Talk abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#talk-abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the R Markdown ecosystem for computational notebooks that support the full lifecycle of scientific communication, including basic reports, presentations, peer-reviewed journal article submissions, and long-form books. The ecosystem has roots in the Pandoc open source project, and includes a family of R packages scientists can use for research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Machine Learning with Tidymodels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-tidymodels-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-tidymodels-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to COVID-19, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sismecbari2021.it/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the conference&lt;/a&gt; was held remotely instead of in Bari, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This six-hour workshop will provide a gentle introduction to machine learning with R using the modern suite of predictive modeling packages called tidymodels. We will build, evaluate, compare, and tune predictive models. Along the way, we’ll learn about key concepts in machine learning including overfitting, the holdout method, the bias-variance trade-off, ensembling, cross-validation, and feature engineering. Learners will gain knowledge about good predictive modeling practices, as well as hands-on experience using tidymodels packages like parsnip, rsample, recipes, yardstick, tune, and workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-earthcube-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-earthcube-panel/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;speakers&#34;&gt;Speakers
  &lt;a href=&#34;#speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenton McHenry (University of Illinois) and Dan Katz (University of Illinois) will moderate a discussion with presenters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alison Hill (RStudio),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Holdgraf (2i2c - Jupyter),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Erdmann (American Geophysical Union), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loren Shure (MathWorks - Matlab).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talks will focus on the latest developments in each of the presenters&amp;rsquo; technologies, emphasizing elements that support the notions of ease of use, long-term executability, interoperability, and software publication. Lessons learned from building a geoscience-focused notebook directory,  notebook template, and long-term preservation in AGU’s ESSOaR will also be discussed - as well as how this all relates to international efforts to elevate notebooks and make them FAIR. This session has been designed for attendees that are already developing notebooks, those interested in doing so, and organizers who want to support these technologies in their events and proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduce yourself online with blogdown &amp; Hugo Apéro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-iyo-tunis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-iyo-tunis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You should have a website!&amp;rdquo; You may have heard this one before, or even said it yourself. In this workshop, you’ll learn how to build and customize a website from the comfort of the RStudio IDE with R Markdown. We&amp;rsquo;ll use the blogdown package and the Hugo Apéro theme to build and deploy a personal website. We’ll cover basic website care and feeding like using R Markdown to create content, how to use GitHub for version control and Netlify for publishing, and how to use the latest upgrades to the blogdown R package to keep your site up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this workshop is to equip participants with tools that amplify their own contributions, build a more visible presence in the R/data community, and share their knowledge and insights with others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free &amp; Open Source Software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-foss-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-foss-panel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting Kind Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-ares-kind-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-ares-kind-tools/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all tool-makers. If you are an educator, your lessons are tools. You make them to be used by students. Students use your lessons to build mental models piece-by-piece, and learn processes step-by-step. If you are a researcher, you design experiments as tools to be used by participants. As a scientist, your analyses are tools used by other researchers to replicate and extend what you did. And finally, if you use software for making any of these tools, you are also using a tool that was crafted by someone else. Is it kind? What makes a tool kind? In this talk, I’ll share ideas and insights I’ve gained while working to make tools for everyday data science communication kinder for users. I’ll discuss some case studies from my work on free and open-source software at RStudio over the past 2.5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making R Markdown work better for you</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-rmd-params/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-rmd-params/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Sad Plot &amp; Make It Better</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-rladies-jozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-rladies-jozi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alison Hill (I think her unofficial nickname is RMarkdown Whisperer) is going to talk to us on another of her strengths. Making things beautiful, and informative. She&amp;rsquo;s going to do her &amp;ldquo;Take a Sad Plot &amp;amp; Make it Better&amp;rdquo; talk, for us. In this talk, Alison will discuss one plot’s life cycle, from a sad Powerpoint slide to the finished product made with the ggplot2 package in R, and what she learnt from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alison doesn&amp;rsquo;t need much introduction, she&amp;rsquo;ll be the main search result if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for RMarkdown info, xaringan inspiration, blogging and teaching online using R, among many other topics! Read about her here: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://alison.rbind.io/about/&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;d learn a lot by following 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/apreshill&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/apreshill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside: Also have a look at Hugo Apéro, for some inspiration on building a presence online (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugo-apero.netlify.app/%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://hugo-apero.netlify.app/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduce yourself online</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-rstudio-global/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2021-rstudio-global/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“You should have a website!” You may have heard this one before, or even said it yourself. In this workshop, you’ll learn how to build and customize a website from the comfort of the RStudio IDE using the blogdown package. We’ll also cover basic website care and feeding like using R Markdown to create content, and how to use GitHub and Netlify to improve your workflow. Pre-work will be shared with participants ahead of time, but to get the most out of this workshop, you’ll want to have a GitHub account and be able to push and pull files from a GitHub repository using your local RStudio IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this workshop is to equip participants with tools that amplify their own contributions, build a more visible presence in the R/data community, and share their knowledge and insights with others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The download</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-larug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-larug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The R Markdown family of packages has grown a lot over the past few years! While each new package is truly a bundle of joy, the past few months we have worked hard to make our family of existing packages more consistent, supportive, and intuitive. In this talk, I’ll share some of what we are up to lately and what to expect, with highlights from the distill, blogdown, bookdown, and xaringan packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InspiRing InstRuction: A panel on teaching #rstats for all audiences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rladies-chicago-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rladies-chicago-panel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone in your department, company, or class comes to you and says: &amp;ldquo;I want to learn R; where do I start?&amp;rdquo; Or, &amp;ldquo;how do I take my R skills to the next level?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come hear from 3 R-Ladies on how to make R pedagogy work for different groups of people!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown for Pharma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rmd4pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rmd4pharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A four-hour workshop that will take you on a tour of how to get from data to manuscript using R Markdown. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basics of Markdown and knitr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to add tables for different outputs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workflows for working with data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to include and style graphics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://themockup.blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tom Mock&lt;/a&gt; from RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning without a net</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-latinr-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-latinr-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I shared my experiences learning new data science skills on my own, and some broader strategies for learning when you have to do it by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching in Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rstudio-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rstudio-tip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This goal of this workshop is to equip educators with the tools that can help them make their teaching more robust and reproducible with R Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trainings offered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020-09-23&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020-09-20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Machine Learning with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rmedicine-tidyml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rmedicine-tidyml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This four-hour workshop will provide a gentle introduction to machine learning with R using the modern suite of predictive modeling packages called 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tidymodels&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidymodels&lt;/a&gt;. We will build, evaluate, compare, and tune predictive models. Along the way, we’ll learn about key concepts in machine learning including overfitting, the holdout method, the bias-variance trade-off, ensembling, cross-validation, and feature engineering. Learners will gain knowledge about good predictive modeling practices, as well as hands-on experience using tidymodels packages like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tidymodels.github.io/parsnip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;parsnip&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tidymodels.github.io/rsample&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rsample&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tidymodels.github.io/recipes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tidymodels.github.io/yardstick/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;yardstick&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tidymodels.github.io/tune/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tune&lt;/a&gt;, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tidymodels.github.io/workflows/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;workflows&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was adapted from a 2-day in-person workshop delivered at rstudio::conf(2020) in San Francisco, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R Markdown for the CDC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rmd4cdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rmd4cdc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R Markdown is an authoring format that enables easy creation of dynamic documents, presentations, and reports from R. It combines the core syntax of markdown with embedded R code chunks that are run so their output can be included in the final document. R Markdown documents are fully reproducible and can be updated whenever underlying R code or data changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great opportunity to learn and get inspired about the capabilities for generating reports in R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will introduce flexible and powerful tools for sharing your research and reports, covering topics like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The basics of R Markdown and knitting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Output formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Options for sharing R Markdown reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will introduce R Markdown and include an overview of the core content types one can create, such as websites, PDF&amp;rsquo;s, PowerPoints, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prior knowledge of R or RStudio is needed to attend this session. There is no registration required for this Webinar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing on Short Notice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-sharing-short-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-sharing-short-notice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This webinar was designed to help educators who needed to quickly transition to remote teaching due to COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educators create a lot of files for teaching- slides, exercises, solutions, assignments, data, figures- that all ultimately need to be shared with other people. Having a link for sharing your teaching materials can save you time and pain, but it is hard to get started if you’ve never shared your resources online before. In this webinar, we’ll give a tour of the R Markdown ecosystem for educators that you can start to use right away. We’ll show how it can help you make your teaching more shareable, reproducible, and resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the accompanying Q&amp;amp;A blog post on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://education.rstudio.com/blog/2020/04/sharing-on-short-notice/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RStudio Education blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Machine Learning with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rsc-tidyml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2020-rsc-tidyml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This two-day workshop provided a gentle introduction to supervised machine learning: concepts, methods, and R code. Participants learned how to train and assess predictive models with several common machine learning algorithms, as well as how to do feature engineering to improve the predictive accuracy of their models. We focused on teaching intuitive explanations of the models and best practices for predictive modeling. Along the way, we introduced several core 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tidymodels&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidymodels&lt;/a&gt; packages, which provide a grammar for modeling that makes it easy to the right thing, and harder to accidentally do the wrong thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plot Twist: 10 Bake Offs, Visualized 11 Ways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rladies-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rladies-sydney/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using data from 10 series of The Great British Bake Off, we will walk through eleven ways to visualize the same data using the &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; package. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk a lot about geoms and variable mappings, but also about what it means to &amp;ldquo;tidy your data&amp;rdquo;, plus the new pivot functions in the &lt;code&gt;tidyr&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You won&amp;rsquo;t need your laptops but you will get the most out of this talk if you know some basics about using &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;. To brush up (or start learning now), you may want to play with the free RStudio.cloud 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.cloud/learn/primers/3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data visualization primer&lt;/a&gt; (you may use an existing Google or GitHub account to log in). Or of course you can check out 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rladiessydney.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R-Ladies Sydney&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s own 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rladiessydney.org/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VizW(h)iz Module&lt;/a&gt; of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rladiessydney.org/ryouwithme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#RYouWithMe&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Literate Projecting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-keynote/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-keynote/index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-keynote/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-keynote/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;“Literate programming” is an approach to writing software programs that weaves together the source code and documentation at the time of creation. The idea is to create programs that are easier for users to understand. But they are also easier for programmers to work on and maintain. In this talk, I will describe how data scientists can be inspired by this programming approach and start what I refer to as “literate projecting.” Literate projects are not only more pleasant to work on — they are also easier for others to discover and explore. In my experiences as a researcher and now a data scientist at RStudio, I’ve had the pleasure to work on many literate projects, and I’ve felt the pain of working on illiterate ones too. What is the difference? What are the benefits? Based on my experiences, I’ll share good literate projecting practices that have the potential to shift your mindset and reshape your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicating with R Markdown Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-workshop/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-workshop/index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-workshop/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-ysc-workshop/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A full-day workshop for &lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-r-project&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; users who want to get more out of &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;R Markdown&lt;/a&gt; (and friends). In this workshop, you will create, publish, and share some beautiful data products. You’ll learn to make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parameterized reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version-controlled R Markdown projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates within a package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shareable &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.github.io/distill/basics.html&#34;&gt;scientific/technical articles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/rmarkdown/xaringan.html&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/flexdashboard/&#34;&gt;dashboards&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/rmarkdown/websites.html&#34;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Sad Plot &amp; Make It Better</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rladies-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rladies-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Alison will talk about one plot’s life cycle, from a sad Powerpoint slide to an Excel chart and finally to the finished product made with the ggplot2 package in R. Along the way, she will discuss why each version of the plot fails in different ways and how each iteration improved on the last one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://apreshill.github.io/ohsu-biodatavis/slides_files/figure-html/animated.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h1 id=&#34;latest-event&#34;&gt;Latest event
  &lt;a href=&#34;#latest-event&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.netlify.com/rlm-sad-plot-better/unsw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This talk&lt;/a&gt; was most recently given at the University of South Wales on 2019/10/04.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown for Medicine Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rmed-rmd4medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rmed-rmd4medicine/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rmed-rmd4medicine/index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rmed-rmd4medicine/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rmed-rmd4medicine/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Students to Talk about Data Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-jsm-talk-ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 14:00:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-jsm-talk-ds/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-jsm-talk-ds/index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-jsm-talk-ds/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-jsm-talk-ds/index_files/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Data science educators have a unique opportunity to teach students the skills they need in their future careers. We know that practical skills matter, like being able to wrangle, explore, analyze, and visualize data (preferably using code), but what is easy to overlook is teaching students how to communicate about data science with other people. Being able to communicate about data, code, and insights gained are important skills we can strengthen in the classroom to make a real impact on students. I will talk about three ways to help strengthen data science communication skills that matter: self-reflection, iteration, and broadcasting. Self-reflection involves asking students to reflect on concepts and/or code that they struggled with to increase engagement with materials and independent problem-solving. Iteration involves revisiting old concepts/code, identifying areas for improvement, and making them better, either independently or in collaboration with peers or other experts/advanced users. Broadcasting involves practice (practice, practice, practice) “wrapping up” code with words into coherent narratives about what a data analysis or visualization means.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 04</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hands-on workshop to creating a personal website using blogdown and the Hugo Academic theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four daily 1-hour sessions (see slides) plus 30-60 minutes of homework for 3 nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the project link for all the days of the summer of blogdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hands-on workshop to creating a personal website using blogdown and the Hugo Academic theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four daily 1-hour sessions (see slides) plus 30-60 minutes of homework for 3 nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the project link for all the days of the summer of blogdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hands-on workshop to creating a personal website using blogdown and the Hugo Academic theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four daily 1-hour sessions (see slides) plus 30-60 minutes of homework for 3 nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the project link for all the days of the summer of blogdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 01</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hands-on workshop to creating a personal website using blogdown and the Hugo Academic theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four daily 1-hour sessions (see slides) plus 30-60 minutes of homework for 3 nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the project link for all the days of the summer of blogdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown to Connect Beyond the Classroom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-sdss-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-sdss-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet blogdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet bookdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-bookdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-bookdown/</guid>
      <description>



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet flexdashboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-flexdashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-flexdashboard/</guid>
      <description>



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet xaringan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-xaringan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2019-rsc-xaringan/</guid>
      <description>



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2018-uo-plotoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2018-uo-plotoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using one dataset from The Great British Bake Off, I show eleven ways to visualize one dataset using eleven different versions of &amp;ldquo;tidy data.&amp;rdquo; Take-away messages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidy data is the start of your data wrangling journey, not the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is not a single &amp;ldquo;tidy&amp;rdquo; version of a dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidy data &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; make you more nimble!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Magic with R: Creative Learning Beyond Fear</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2018-cascadia-bigmagic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2018-cascadia-bigmagic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the book “Big Magic: Creative Living Beyond Fear” by Elizabeth Gilbert, Alison will talk about the five essential ingredients needed to creatively learn R and why these elements are also essential for advanced users to take their R skills to the next level. You will hear practical advice for when, where, and how to start a project in R, and how your learning can add value- both to your own knowledge and to contribute to the larger community of R learners. Along the way, she will share recommended resources and evidence-based strategies for project-based learning. Alison’s background working with both new and advanced R users gives her a unique perspective on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Sad Plot &amp; Make It Better</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2018-ohsu-sad-plot-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2018-ohsu-sad-plot-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us on April 6 for a walk-through of how to take a sad plot and make it better by Alison Hill, who co-teaches the CS631 Data Visualization course. Alison will take us through one plot’s life cycle, from a sad Powerpoint slide to an Excel chart and finally to the finished product made with the ggplot2 package in R. We will discuss why each version of the plot fails in different ways, how each iteration improved on the last one, and which data visualization principles are at work in the final plot to communicate a clear scientific story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://apreshill.github.io/ohsu-biodatavis/slides_files/figure-html/animated.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this, Eric Earl (Senior RA in the DCAN Labs) will show a case study of visualization in neuroimaging research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labhub Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2017-ohsu-labhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2017-ohsu-labhub/</guid>
      <description>




  
  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2017-ohsu-labhub/ohsu-os-panel_hu7d76264941752927e3f4d28cdfb202dc_337688_2000x2000_fit_box_3.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2017-ohsu-labhub/ohsu-os-panel_hu7d76264941752927e3f4d28cdfb202dc_337688_2000x2000_fit_box_3.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;830&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landscape of scientific communication is changing dramatically.  Diverse stakeholders, including major funders and universities are demonstrating a growing interest and investment in open scientific principles and practices.  Researchers, students, and the institutions that support them are needing to navigate new expectations, workflows, and policies against a backdrop of relatively unchanged means and measures of scientific success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound complicated?  Join us on December 8th from 3:00 to 4:00 PM for a panel discussion with OHSU leaders and early career researchers on the evolving landscape of scientific communication.  We’ll explore the drivers behind the calls for “openness”, what this means in practice, and the real world compatibility and tensions between open science and student, researcher, and institutional success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confirmed panelists include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Gary Westbrook, Vollum Institute Senior Scientist and Director of the Neuroscience Graduate Program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bita Moghaddam, Chair of the Department of Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Abhinav Nellore, Assistant Professor, Biomedical Engineering and the Department of Surgery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Alison Hill, Associate Professor, Center for Spoken Language Understanding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel will be followed by food, drinks, and two hands on workshops from 4:00 - 5:30:&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;ohsu-os-labhub-workshop.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;ohsu-os-labhub-workshop.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this workshop, Dr. Alison Hill and Robin Champieux demonstrated tools and methods for building transparency within a lab, and onboarding new graduate students and postdocs. We provided a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apreshill/labhub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;template GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and code of conduct designed to facilitate a healthy and productive learning and research environment. You are encouraged to use these tools to communicate expectations, document protocols, receive feedback, and facilitate the long-term value of students’ and trainees’ contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labhub is a &lt;em&gt;work in progress&lt;/em&gt;. We created 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apreshill/labhub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this repository&lt;/a&gt; as an education and demonstration tool for faculty, postdocs, and students curious about how documentation, open science workflows, and tools like Github can contribute to a healthy and productive research environment. Your ideas and contributions are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up &amp; Running with blogdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2017-pdxr-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2017-pdxr-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See project links for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Your Graph Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/2016-ohsu-dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/2016-ohsu-dataviz/</guid>
      <description>




  
  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2016-ohsu-dataviz/code-your-graph_hu9ebcd1d99c0a236c25b6db9f0e87e85d_160690_2000x2000_fit_q75_box.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/talk/2016-ohsu-dataviz/code-your-graph_hu9ebcd1d99c0a236c25b6db9f0e87e85d_160690_2000x2000_fit_q75_box.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


